Guide to the Arthur Bridgman Clark Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Arthur Bridgman Clark papers
1904-1931
SC0275
Clark, Arthur Bridgman, 1866-1948
8 Linear feet
Collection includes genealogical material relating to the family of Professor Arthur B. Clark; "Drawings and notes of a motor trip" through Europe, Spain and Morocco in 1931-32 by Arthur B. Clark and Grace Clark (printed volumes, letters, original drawings, and prints); financial records, 1906-1921, and miscellaneous papers, 1864-1904; and original woodblocks, prints and copper plates by Professor Clark.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Dr. Esther Clark, 1982.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Head of the Department of Art, Professor Clark taught at Stanford from 1893 until his retirement in 1931. He specialized in the printing method.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes genealogical material relating to the family of Professor Arthur B. Clark; "Drawings and notes of a motor trip" through Europe, Spain and Morocco in 1931-32 by Arthur B. Clark and Grace Clark (printed volumes, letters, original drawings, and prints); financial records, 1906-1921, and miscellaneous papers, 1864-1904; and original woodblocks, prints and copper plates by Professor Clark.
Access Terms
Clark, Arthur Bridgman, 1866-1948; Stanford University. Department of Art. Faculty.; Europe --Description and travel.; Morocco --Description and travel.; Spain --Description and travel.; Woodblocks.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - 3 copies of Clark's Family Genealogy (unbound). (Box 1)
  - 1 folder of miscellaneous sheets and correspondence related to the Genealogy. (Box 1)
  - Stanford Illustrated Review issue containing an article on Clark becoming Professor Emeritus., 1931 Jun (Box 1)
  - “Drawings and Notes of a Motor Trip” (unbound pamphlets), Vol. I (3 copies), Vol. II (3 copies), Vol. III (2 copies), Vol. IV (1 Copy). (Box 1)
  - Negatives of photos for the Genealogy, etc. (Box 1)
  - Manuscript letters and drawings of the 1931-32 trip through Europe. (Box 2)
  - Original printing plates (woodblocks and etched plates). (Box 3)
  - Original printing plates (woodblocks and etched plates). (Box 4)
  - Original printing plates (woodblocks and etched plates). (Box 5)
  - Original printing plates (woodblocks and etched plates). (Box 6)
  - Account book pages, circa 1906-1907 (Box 7)
  - Misc. accounts, 1906-1908 (Box 7)
  - Bond statements (Box 7)
  - Misc. financial papers, 1917-1921 (Box 7)
  - Mayfield Board of Trade brochure, 1904 (Box 7)
  - Ilion Agricultural Works price list, 1864 (Box 7)